Who are you?
你是誰？
I am myself!
我是…我自己！
Why are the gangsters after you?
-為什麼黑社會要追殺妳？ -我不知道
-Who are you? -I can't remember!
-妳到底是誰？ -我想不起來
Where is the kid?
那小鬼在哪裡？
Don't feign ignorance!
你別再裝傻了
After he tells you, kill him.
他說了之後，就殺了他
Don't be defeated until you win.
在妳贏之前，千萬別輸
Mr. Akagi.
赤城先生
Someone in the neighborhood reported this.
附近有人通知我，我要把她帶走了
Don't worry. You can trust him.
不用怕，妳可以相信他
It's not in the newspaper today either?
今天也沒有刊登嗎？
He took a vacation?
什麼？放假？
Yeah, Mr. Akagi is on vacation.
是，赤城先生在休假
I'd like to know whether the kidnapped child
那個…我想知道 被綁架的孩子現在安不安全
-Kidnapped? -Yes.
-綁架？ -是的
Nothing has been said about it in the newspaper and the news.
報紙沒有報導，電視新聞也沒有
What are you talking about? Kidnap?
你在說什麼綁架？
It's the case from two days ago which Mr. Akagi is in charge of.
就是前天赤城先生負責的綁架案
Mr. Akagi's holiday started three days ago.
赤城先生三天前就開始放假了
But…
但是…
What?
什麼？
KARAOKE BOX URARA
（KTV麗）
But this is strange, somehow…
但我總覺得有點奇怪
It's like this case has never existed.
好像整件事沒發生過似的
Mr. Akagi was on leave on that day.
那天赤城先生也是在休假
It's not unusual.
那很平常吧？
I mean for detectives to work on cases on vacation.
警察常要在放假時跑腿的
He used to do this when he was dealing with us, too.
我們那時候也常常這樣
"My daughter has her sports day today!"
“今天是我女兒的運動會 你們居然敢給我搗亂？”
-I'm sorry! -Like that.
-對不起 -像這樣
I know, but…
我知道…
But Hikari was…
但是她…日花里…
Officer…
警察先生…
Hey, you…
喂，妳…
She was very frightened of policemen.
她很怕警察
What's wrong with you, Keebou?
怎麼了，希少？
Don't tell me that you distrust Mr. Akagi?
別告訴我你在懷疑赤城先生
-No, I'm not doubtful… -Have you forgotten this?
-我不是說懷疑… -你忘了嗎？
Have you forgotten how much Mr. Akagi helped us?
赤城先生有多照顧我們幾個
He even found me my job.
-他甚至還替我找工作 -我沒忘記啊
I haven't forgotten it, but…
-我沒忘記，但是… -不是只有我們吧？
We're not the only ones who owe Mr. Akagi a lot.
這鎮上有很多人
-Also lots of people in this town. -I know!
-欠赤城先生人情吧 -我知道
But…
不過…
Oh, Kayo!
好，小佳代
Anyway, we've done the right thing to leave this to Mr. Akagi.
總之，交給赤城先生處理 準沒錯，聽到了嗎？
Kayo!
小佳代
Don't worry.
沒事的
Mr. Akagi doesn't do anything bad.
那個赤城先生不會做壞事的
I wonder if the Board of Education can look up a child's address…
不知道教育委員會 能不能查到那孩子的住址？
I mean…
現在我媽的丈夫 在縣內的教育委員會工作
Don't do this, Keebou.
算了吧，希少
Nothing good will come out of it even if you do that.
你做這種事也不會有好結果的
Hey!
喂！
I don't know…
我不知道…
Where have you put it?
那東西在哪裡？
Is it here?
在那裡嗎？
Give me that!
給我
Let's see.
我看看
Darn!
可惡
Poor teddy bear.
真可憐
The guys are so cruel.
這些叔叔真過份
Hikari.
日花里
Where is it? Tell me.
它在哪兒？告訴我
Come on, tell me.
來…告訴我
Hikari, tell me where it is.
日花里，告訴我在哪裡
Please help me!
拜託您了
I know very well that this is an unreasonable request.
我非常清楚這個要求很不合理
But… Please help me!
但是請你想想辦法
What is your reason?
理由是什麼？
I desperately want to know where she lives. I'm worried about her.
我一定要知道她住在哪裡 我真的很擔心她
I'm repeating myself, but…
我再重複說一遍
I cannot reveal a child's personal data.
我不能向你透漏兒童的個人資料
I will definitely not cause you any trouble, Mr. Segawa.
我絕對不會給瀨川先生您添麻煩的
I promise!
我向您保證
Kiichi…
希一
Don't trouble your father.
別讓你爸爸為難了
Of course it's impossible.
那是絕對不行的
Kiichi. Please.
希一，拜託你了
Where is it?
到底在哪裡呢？
I don't know.
不知道
I really don't know.
我真的不知道
I hate it when children lie!
叔叔我最討厭撒謊的小孩了
It's not a lie… I'm not lying.
我沒撒謊…我真的沒有
Hikari, do you love your dad?
日花里，妳愛爸爸嗎？
Dad…
爸爸？
Can you really not remember it?
妳真的不記得嗎？
Darling.
老公
I wonder when Kiichi will call me…
不知道希一 什麼時候才願意叫我一聲爸爸…
Well,
不過，我也不能說他
I still can't call Kiichi by his name yet, either.
我也是到現在還不能直接叫他希一
Darling…
老公
Don't do anything stupid.
你別做傻事
It was the first time, Sumiko.
那是第一次啊，澄子
It was the first time…
他第一次…
that he had asked me to do something for him.
拜託我替他做些什麼事情
But he couldn't even give you a good reason…
可是他連詳細的理由也沒說…
He could have made up as many reasons as possible.
理由這種東西 要捏造的話，要幾個就能有幾個
But Kiichi did not do that.
但希一並沒有那麼做
You know…
妳知道嗎？
I love him.
我很喜歡他
I think I love him much more than you think.
我想，我比妳想的還要喜歡他
Listen.
聽著
If you say anything unnecessary…
要是妳說了多餘的話…
Sorry that I've frightened you.
嚇著了妳，對不起
But I'm betting my life on this.
可是…
HOTEL EIKOKUKAN
（英國館飯店）
What have you been listening to?
你在聽什麼？
Shiho…
小志穗
-I think our relationship… -I don't want to hear that.
-我們的關係還是… -我不想聽
Shiho, you…
但小志穗…
Say, can you remember anything about your school?
妳能想起些什麼嗎？
Thank you very much.
真的非常謝謝您
CASHIER
（批價處）
-How much is it? -48000 yen, please.
-多少錢？ -48000元
-Let's go. -Take care.
-走吧 -請保重
Please think about this.
如果可以的話，請考慮一下
Let's go.
走吧
TO WASHIO CENTRAL HOSPITAL
（介紹敝社新機種）
Okay…
好…
There you go.
給妳
It's dirty now…
袖子髒了
Don't worry.
沒關係的，我有朋友開洗衣店
-This is for you. -No, it's okay…
-給你 -不用了，那個…
Where did you get this?
妳是在哪裡找到這個的？
A ten-year-old girl…
十歲的女孩…
Officer?
警察？
Is the police officer over 50 years old…
那個警察是過了50歲…
It's our patient's personal information, we can't reveal more.
這是病患的個人資料 我們不能再告訴你了
-But… -I said…
-可是… -都說不行了
What's the matter with the girl?
那個孩子怎麼了嗎？
Well, she…
那個…有點…
Do you happen to know her address or…
那個孩子的住址之類的…
Of course I can't tell you.
這絕對不能告訴你
I knew it…
說的也是
Yes.
是的
Her memory is repressed because of high levels of stress and shock…
由於過度的壓力和受了驚嚇 而引起的壓抑性健忘…
That is, so-called amnesia.
應該就是所謂的失憶症
Keebou…
希少…
Don't cry!
別哭，拿出勇氣來，妳一定會贏的
Until you win…
在妳贏之前
Don't be defeated.
千萬別輸
Don't be defeated until I win.
在贏之前千萬別輸
Until I win…
在贏之前…
Caught you.
抓到妳了
MIKI TIRES
（三木腳踏車）
What? Sneak into the hospital?
什麼？潛入醫院？
Yeah, so…
對，所以…
I need someone to keep watch for me.
我要人替我把風
So I was wondering if you would help me…
所以我想，你能不能幫幫忙…
What are you, an idiot? That's a criminal offense!
你瘋了嗎？那可是犯罪啊
But it's the only way to find out where Hikari is.
那是唯一能知道日花里在哪裡的方法
I mean, Mikki, this is really fishy.
米奇，這件事絕對有問題
Why did a policeman accompany her to the hospital now?
為什麼她現在還要跟警察去醫院？
Shouldn't it be her parents?
正常不是該父母陪嗎？
-I mean, her kidnap… -Keebou!
-我想，就連說她被綁架… -希少
Are you a little too engrossed with this?
你會不會太熱心了？
What do you mean by too engrossed?
你說什麼太熱心？
You have saved the girl from Tagawa and the gangsters.
我們從田川他們手上 救了那孩子，那就夠了吧？
-But Mikki… -I say, don't do this!
-可是，米奇… -我叫你不要去
You shouldn't do any more.
再插手太危險了
I just have this feeling.
我有這種感覺
CALLER: MIKKI
（米奇來電）
Hey!
搞什麼？
-It's a woman, right? -No, it's Mikki.
-是女人吧？ -不是，那是米奇
-That's a woman. -That would be Minnie.
-那就是女人了 -女的就叫米妮了
Ma'am.
太太
Put it… here first, okay?
妳要先放在…這裡，好嗎？
You did it again?
你又來了？
How many times do I have to tell you?
我要說幾次你才懂？
Your job is,
你的工作是確認店內有順手牽羊犯後
-to catch them in the act. -I'm sorry.
-再在他們犯案時抓住他們 -對不起
Gosh, you're useless!
你真沒用
I would have fired you ages ago
要不是那警察介紹你來的 我早就開除你了
I'm sorry.
對不起
CALLER: MIKKI
（米奇來電）
What? Seriously? Keebou is still saying that?
什麼？真的？希少他還在說那種話？
But that would mean trouble.
再說，那也太危險了吧？
Of course I stopped him.
我當然阻止過他了 但我想他不會服氣的
Stop him if he calls you.
他打給你的話，就阻止他吧
Choco? I called him, but he didn't answer.
巧克力？我打給他了，可是他不接啊
Yes? A nutcracker?
什麼？胡桃鉗？
Why? But you got a nutcracker along with the pan.
為什麼？最近買平底鍋時 才送了一個開核桃器吧？
But it is not a doll!
可是那個不是娃娃啊
Please! Pichan, can I click "buy"? Please!
求求你，小皮，可以買嗎？我要買
-How much? -29,800 yen.
-多少錢？ -29800元
That's expensive! Saya, do you really need that?
好貴！
PASSED THE TEST PUPPY-CHAN NO. TWO
（考試合格的巴比）
I can't buy it?
不能買嗎？
I'm sorry… I keep buying useless things…
對不起，紗彩總是買沒用的東西回家
No… That's not what I mean.
不，不是那樣的
Okay. You can buy it.
我知道了，好吧，妳買吧
Okay. Click "buy".
嗯，買吧
Oh, ma'am! I'd like to change the tempura soba to soba in soup.
歐巴桑，我還是不要天婦羅蕎麥麵 要湯蕎麥麵好了
This is ridiculous!
你這是怎麼搞的？
-Yes? What would you like… -Pi? It's me.
-怎麼了？這次又是… -小皮？是我
What? It's you?
搞什麼，是你啊？
-Don't be ridiculous, stupid Pon! -Why are you mad so suddenly?
-你別跟我開玩笑，死碰將 -你怎麼突然對我發脾氣？
Keebou won't change his mind once he has made it up.
希少一旦決定了 就不會聽別人說什麼了
Yeah…
對啊…
I hope he'll get hold of Mr. Akagi soon and find out how the girl is.
快點聯絡上赤城先生 知道那孩子怎麼樣就好了
Can we meet tomorrow?
明天能見面嗎？
Let's end this.
我們不要再見了，好嗎？
-The relationship isn't healthy. -I'll die.
-我還是覺這種關係不太好 -我會去死
I'll die if you break up with me.
你跟我分手，我就去死
That again?
妳又來了
I'm serious.
我是認真的
If you're gone in my life I'm all on my own.
你不在我身邊的話 我就孤伶伶一個人了
Living is pointless.
活下來也沒意義
-You have a husband. -It doesn't matter!
-妳有丈夫吧？ -那完全無關
The depths of loneliness
物理上的孤獨和精神上的孤獨 深度完全不同
What? What are you saying?
妳…在說什麼？
You are my everything, Shuntaro.
你是我的一切，春太郎
Mikki!
好痛…米奇？
What… Huh?
什麼？
HAYASHIDA LAUNDRY SHOP
（林田洗衣店）
Did Mikki call you all here?
-米奇，是你叫他們來的？ -我沒有，他們自己跟來的
-Why would I take so much trouble? -Then why did you come?
-別特地來啊 -你才不要來
Just so you know, we're not here to help you.
先說好，我們不是來幫你的
I see.
是嗎？
Why are you so engrossed with this?
我說你，為什麼那麼熱心？
I'm not engrossed. I'm just worried.
我也不是熱心… 我只是擔心而已，沒什麼特別
You mean you don't trust Mr. Akagi? Because he didn't answer his phone?
你是說你不相信赤城先生？
-That's exactly what you mean. -No!
-你就是這個意思 -我不是
Guys, stop fighting.
你們兩個別吵了
I don't want to regret anymore…
我不想再後悔了
just because I give up something half way.
做事情半途而廢
I want to watch something I've been involved in to its end.
自己參與過的事，我希望能做到底
Sorry, I know you've taken the trouble to come and stop me.
對不起，你們特地來阻止我 卻讓你們白走一趙
Thank you.
謝了
Will you be happy if you have had a look at her?
看一眼你就滿意了嗎？
Yes?
什麼？
Sneak a peek at the girl and her mom playing in the garden
去偷窺那孩子和媽媽一起在花園
and be mistaken as a pervert, will you be happy then?
然後被當成變態，那你就高興了嗎？
You're such a nuisance!
你這傢伙還真夠麻煩的
You'll treat me to Banraiken's intestine set meal, okay?
-萬來軒的內臟定食，你請 -什麼？
You'll treat us to the intestine set meal? Why didn't you say it sooner?
你會請吃內臟定食？怎麼不早說？
-In for a penny, in for a meal. -In for a penny, in for a pound?
-一不吃，二不休 -是“一不做”
It's too late to turn back the horse.
騎馬難下了
It's the ship.
是“騎虎”
Okay. I'll join, too.
好吧，那我也要參加
I haven't had the intestine set meal for a long time.
我很久沒吃內臟定食了
-Guys, do you know what you're doing? -I'm sorry…
-你們真的知道自己在幹嘛嗎？ -對不起…我不能接電話
I didn't get it from your voice message,
不過聽你的留言也聽不懂
What are we doing? Why are we assembling here?
這是要做什麼？約出來幹嘛？
Guys…
那個…
This will actually catch people's eyes.
這樣反而更引人注目
I mean, even Kayo is here…
-連小佳代也來了 -問題是如何突破那裡
Let's get someone to be the bait.
要找人作餌嗎？
-Oh! You'll go. -Why me?
-你去 -為什麼要我去？
-What are we doing? -Choco!
-對了，我們在幹嘛？ -巧克力，別吵
Kayo, no!
小佳代，不要…
Oh, ma'am? What's the matter?
老奶奶，妳怎麼了？
-Have you eaten yet? -Yes?
-你還沒吃飯嗎？ -什麼？
Hang on, ma'am…
等…等一下，老奶奶
I did feed her.
我明明就餵飽她了啊
Well done, Kayo! Let's go…
小佳代，做得好，我們走吧
Don't come with us. Please take care of my grandma.
-你別跟來，奶奶拜託你了 -什麼？
What?
不是吧？
-Whoa! -What?
什麼？
Where is your destination?
我們要去哪裡？
Then where is that?
-那是哪裡？ -不知道
What? Don't tell me you didn't plan this. You're such an idiot!
什麼？你居然沒計劃？ 你到底有多笨啊？
-Hey… What are we doing? -Shush! What?
-告訴我，我們在做什麼？ -巧克力，別吵
I got it.
我知道了，先去小兒科好了
-What? -You're right.
-什麼？ -你說得對
-What are you doing? -Oops…
-你們在這裡幹什麼？ -糟了…
So? You can't tell me the details,
你說你不能詳細說明理由
but you desperately want to know if the girl is safe?
但一定要知道那孩子是不是安全？
Even if you have to do something so stupid?
就算得做這種蠢事也想確認？
I'm sorry.
對不起
I'm sorry…
對不起…
-What is her name? -Yes?
-名字呢？ -什麼？
If anything really happens to the girl, my conscience will torment me.
如果那孩子真的有危險 我的良心也會不好過
-Then… -But…
-那妳… -不過…
I cannot reveal the girl's address to you.
我絕對不能把住址告訴你們
I will go to her home and see how she is doing. Will that be okay?
我會去她家裡看看，可以嗎？
Thank you!
謝謝妳
Oh, I've found it.
找到了
I'm sorry…
對不起…
The address is…
住址是…
Oh? It's the address of the police station.
咦？怎麼會是警察局的地址？
It says, "taken in by the Numazu Chuo Police Station."
它寫著 “被託管在沼津中央警察局”
Don't worry, Keebou.
沒事的，希少
Isn't it reassuring to know that she's still at the police station?
她還在警察局的話 不是更能放心嗎？
But the policeman I asked didn't know this.
可是我問的警察並不知道
Maybe he has a reason to hide this from his colleagues.
可能他有什麼理由要秘密行動吧？
Well, Mr. Akagi will call us soon.
赤城先生很快就會聯絡我們的
But…
可是…
But this…
可是這個…
I think Hikari dropped it on purpose.
我總覺得
Do you seriously distrust Mr. Akagi?
你是認真地在懷疑赤城先生嗎？
Frankly…
說真的…
I think I do.
我想我是
You really have left us!
離開我們後，你果然變了
We are much closer to Mr. Akagi than you!
我們和你跟赤城先生的感情完全不同
-We're ten years closer! -Ponjara.
-我們比你深十年 -碰將
Stop fighting, both of you.
你們兩個就別再吵了
He had helped me a lot, too.
他以前也很照顧我的
I did so much mischief,
雖然我幹了那麼多壞事
yet I was never sent to the Classification Office.
但也沒被送進過監護所過 都是多虧了赤城先生
When I told him that I passed the university entrance exam,
當我考上大學，向他報告的時候
he was so happy that he wept for joy.
他也高興得流淚了
Why, then?
那為什麼？
-Why don't you trust Mr. Akagi? -I don't want to doubt him either!
-為什麼還要懷疑赤城先生？ -我也不想懷疑他
That's why I want to know the truth as soon as I can.
所以我才想快點知道真相
Guys, sorry for today.
各位，今天對不起了
Keebou…
希少…
CALLER: MR. SEGAWA
（瀨川先生來電）
Hello.
是
It's all right. I took a day off in lieu today.
不要緊，我今天請補假了
Yes?
什麼？
Do you know what you do more frequently when you get older?
知道人老了就會更常做什麼嗎？
It's forgetting things and talking to yourself.
是忘記東西和自言自語
So…
所以呢…
I just forget to hang up the phone and start talking to myself.
我不小心 忘了關上電話就在自言自語了
Oh…
是嗎？那真的不妙啊
Darling…
老公…
So, this is me talking to myself.
所以，這是我在自言自語
Okay?
知道了嗎？
Oh, hang on… Please wait a minute.
那個，請…請等一下
I'm sorry.
不好意思，請把你自言自語的話
What you said to yourself.
再說一遍
Okay.
是
569-1 Minami Ishihara.
南石原569之1
What are you doing, dad?
爸爸，你在做什麼？ 他拿去幹壞事的話怎麼辦？
You are deceived by him! And by this woman, too!
你被那傢伙騙了 還有這女人也在騙你
He was a well-known gangster in this area.
那傢伙以前是這區有名的小混混
This woman hid this fact and made advances to you!
這女人隱瞞了這事實，然後去接近你
You have been deceived all these years!
你一直以來都被他們騙了
I'm sorry.
對不起
I'm sorry, darling, I…
對不起，老公，那個…我…
I knew this.
我早就知道了
Of course I knew that.
這麼小的事，當然瞞不過我
What?
什麼？
Naturally, I did.
那是當然的了
There would be something wrong with me if I didn't.
沒發覺的話才奇怪
And Kiichi, too…
而且希一他…
I knew very well
他到底…
how much effort he had put in
是如何努力把媽媽的謊話變成真話
turning his mother's lie into the truth.
我也非常清楚
I do know this.
我是知道的
What a man he is.
他是個了不起的男人
I am happy and fortunate to have a son like him.
有一個像他那樣的兒子 我真的很幸福
Have you heard that, Kiichi?
聽到了嗎，希一？
This…
剛才的…
I wasn't talking to myself just now, okay?
可不是我在自言自語
Okay.
是的
Thank you!
謝謝你
Mr. Segawa.
瀨川先生…
Dad.
爸爸
Darling…
老公…
What was that?
這是什麼意思？
Having a son like him? Then what am I to you? Who am I?
有他那樣的兒子？ 那我算什麼？我是誰？
People make a laughing stock out of me because of him!
都是因為他，我才會被當笑柄 所以我現在才…
Are you telling me to fight with others? I'm not like him!
你要我打架嗎？我可不像那傢伙…
Fighting with people isn't the only way to fight.
作戰的方法不是只有打架一個
I'm not telling you to fight with the bullies.
我不是叫你去跟欺負你的人打架
In order to get the life you want,
為了得到自己想要的現在
what have you done?
你到底做過什麼？
Yuta!
優太
Are you going out?
要出門嗎？
What are you here for?
你們怎麼來了？
-We'll go to look for her home. -Yes?
-去找那孩子的家吧 -什麼？
In the end we're just like you.
我們也跟你一樣
We don't want to give up half way.
不想半途而廢 參與過的事情，我們也想做到底
Guys…
你們…
I'm sorry, Toru.
對不起，透
I'm sorry…
對不起…
Don't do something that you have to apologize for!
什麼對不起啊？對不起？
Oh, my god!
-嚇死人了 -很危險的，混蛋！
Oh?
咦？
-Thanks, guys. -Thanks, sir.
-辛苦了 -辛苦您了
What do I have to do to make you remember?
妳要怎樣才能想起來？
This is bad.
真傷腦筋
I don't have much time left!
我可沒什麼時間了
For someone in shock it's best to…
驚嚇就要用驚嚇…
make them shocked again!
來做驚嚇療法
HAYASHIDA LAUNDRY SHOP
（林田洗衣店）
Hey…
這…
Is this really the place, Tenten?
你真的找對地方了嗎，典典？
It's like somewhere in the Japanese legends.
這裡有夠像日本傳說裡會出現的地方
The car GPS says it's here.
衛星導航說是在這裡
Oh?
應該是那間吧？
She is living in a house like that?
原來她住在這種地方
Somehow this feels suspicious.
我總覺得有點怪怪的
-What is he doing? -Hold him down!
-他搞什麼？ -制服他
What are you doing?
死小鬼
Let me go!
放開我！
What? A compass?
什麼？圓規？
-It brings back memories. -Let go.
-真懷念這個 -有量角器嗎？
-Let go… -Yuta? Why are you here?
-放開我 -優太？你為什麼…
Do you know him?
你認識他？
He's my younger brother.
是我弟弟
Younger brother?
弟弟？
-Seriously? -What's the matter, Yuta?
-真的假的？ -怎麼了，優太？
Why are you here?
你怎麼會在這裡？
Why are you here? Are you going to steal from the family or rob them?
你來這裡打算幹什麼？
Why?
為什麼？
Why did dad speak so highly
為什麼你這種人…
-of a scum like you? -Shut up!
-像你這樣的人渣，爸爸會… -閉嘴，笨蛋
Scum is someone who uses this in a fight!
會用這東西來打架的才是人渣
I need a weapon to fight with a former gangster.
跟以前的黑道打架要準備武器 這是理所當然的
Yuta…
優太…
-A car is coming! Let's hide! -Okay.
-有車來了，快躲起來 -好
Whoa.
喂
What? Are you running away?
什麼？你們要逃跑嗎？
Watch out!
快點…
Tagawa?
田川？
Why is Tagawa here?
為什麼田川會…
Are they in this together?
田川和赤城先生
Tagawa and Mr. Akagi.
他們是一伙的？
Don't be silly! How is that possible?
別傻了，那怎麼可能？
But if that's the case…
不過如果是真的…
Then it makes sense.
那就說得過去了
We still haven't found it.
還沒有找到
Maybe it isn't here.
可能不是在這裡
Let's move it to somewhere else.
去別的地方吧 再留在這裡，警察會找到這裡來的
Gosh!
真是的…又把我留下來把風
They are keeping a close watch on the place.
他們守衛蠻森嚴的
Who are those guys?
他們是什麼人？
They're not Tagawa's underlings.
也不是田川那邊的人
Guys, look at the second floor.
喂，你們看二樓
Mr. Akagi!
赤城先生
Well, maybe they brought Mr. Akagi here by force…
不，赤城先生可能是被關在那裡…
or maybe not.
看起來不像
Hey! Stop running!
喂，你別跑！
Are they really doing this together?
他們真的是一伙的嗎？
The police and gangsters, huh?
警察和黑道…
What is that nonsense? Of course it's impossible…
你們在說什麼傻話？那怎麼可能…
What are you doing? Casing the joint before you steal?
你們在幹嘛？視察環境去偷竊嗎？
I'll tell dad…
我要告訴爸…
-What are you doing? -Toru!
-喂，你在幹什麼？ -你別吵
Guys, this is bad.
喂，這下不妙了
Keebou, Mikki.
希少、米奇
Go.
去吧
Hikari might be there.
日花里可能在裡面
We'll deal with the small fry.
小角色讓我們來應付
Who are you?
你們是誰？
I am myself…
-我是我自己！
Ow…
好痛…
-I'll leave this to you. -We'll take care of this.
-那拜託你們了 -交給我們吧
Come here!
給我過來！
You're joking…
這不是真的吧…
of course not.
怎麼可能？
What are you doing there, Ponjara?
碰將，你在幹嘛？
It's impossible!
赤城先生不可能做那種事！
Then let's go and find out!
那就去確認一下吧
We'll ask Mr. Akagi about this.
去問赤城先生吧
Those idiots…
這幾個傢伙…
-Go. -Yes, sir.
-去 -是
Hikari!
日花里！
Hikari, are you here?
日花里，妳在嗎？
Answer me if you are!
妳在的話就回答我！
Hikari, don't be defeated!
日花里，不要輸！
As long as you don't admit defeat, you're on your way to win!
只要妳不認輸 妳就是在勝利的途中！
-Be quiet! -Keebou!
-給我安靜點 -希少
Don't be defeated until you win, Hikari!
在妳贏之前，千萬別輸，日花里！
Keebou!
希少！
-Keebou! -Hikari… Hikari!
-希少！ -日花里…
-Hikari!
希少…
Keebou!
希少！
-Keebou! -Hikari!
-希少！ -日花里！
Keebou!
希少！
Go, Keebou!
快去，希少！
Go away, Chancellor.
走開，總長
-Back out of this. -What?
-快走吧 -什麼？
Your opponent is too strong. I'm telling you for your own good.
對手太強了
-I'll decide it myself. -Don't you dare!
-這點我自己會決定 -等一下
-Don't come here! -Keebou…
-別過來 -希少…
Mr. Akagi!
赤城先生…
If you get any closer I'll kill the kid.
你再靠近的話，我就殺了她
What are you doing, Mr. Akagi?
你在做什麼，赤城先生？
Mr. Akagi…
赤城先生
You used to tell us, didn't you?
你不是常對我們說嗎？
That we can fight,
打架是可以
but we can't use violence.
但是不能使用暴力
I am stupid,
我是笨
but I have never forgotten that.
但我從來沒忘記過你說的話
But…
可是…
But why are you doing this, Mr. Akagi?
為什麼赤城先生你會這樣做？
Yeah. I used to do that.
的確是有過這樣的時間
I used to be at your beck and call,
那時你們把我耍得團團轉
you stupid brats!
你們這些死小鬼！
You know,
叔叔我…
I have a daughter, too.
也有一個女兒
She was adorable when she was your age.
她像妳這麼大的時候，真的很可愛
She told me that
她說，她長大以後
she would marry me when she grew up.
要當爸爸的新娘
However…
可是…
Not long after that, she wouldn't even look at me in the eye.
沒過多久
She conspired with my wife,
她勾結我老婆
and treated me like stinky rubbish.
把我…
She told me I should die for my job,
說什麼會有一筆撫恤金給她
because she would get the compensation money.
所以叫我不如直接殉職算了
It's horrible, isn't it?
很過份吧？
Mr. Akagi…
赤城先生
I don't want to fight with you.
我們不想跟你打
I won't.
我不會打
Keebou,
希少
can't you see this?
沒看到這個嗎？
The moment you shoot,
你一開槍，你就肯定會輸了
A cop's gun only has five bullets, right?
警察的手槍
There are six of us here.
我們有六個人
Even if you shoot us dead one by one,
就算你一槍一個的打死我們
the one who survives will get Hikari out
剩下的那個也一定會救日花里 然後把你交給警察
It's simple.
綽綽有餘了
You still haven't changed, Keebou.
你還是沒變，希少
What is the point of my life?
我的人生到底算什麼？
What little there is of my salary is all spent by others,
微薄的薪水被人亂花
my wife and child look down on me…
老婆和孩子都小看我，可是…
spending every penny I've saved.
我存起來的錢都被花光了
I have no dream and no hope.
我是既沒希望，也沒夢想了
Mr. Akagi…
赤城先生…
But it suddenly came to me.
但是它降臨在我身上了
A chance to start my life again.
一個讓我重新開始人生的機會
Why wouldn't I do it?
你會抓住這個機會吧？
Of course I'd do it! It's a lot of money!
當然會做了，有很大的一筆錢啊
Mr. Akagi, you're joking, right?
不是吧，赤城先生？
You do this for money?
居然是為了錢？
You do such horrible thing just for money?
你就是為了錢，幹這種事情？
What else can there be?
還會是為了什麼？
Frankly, only money matters! Everything is about money!
當然是錢了！是錢…
Listen. Remember this.
聽我說，你們好好記著
People say that money can't buy everything, but it's a lie!
有人說有東西是錢買不到的 那是騙你的，什麼都買得到！
Friendship, love… Everything!
友情、愛情…全部都能！
But on the contrary,
不過相反…
if you have no money all of these…
沒有錢的話，那些東西全部…
just run away and disappear.
全都不知道逃到哪兒去了
You said this when you referred me for my job,
但你在介紹工作給我的時候 不是說過嗎？
that although the salary is low, money isn't everything!
你說雖然薪水是低 但它的意義不在金錢
Because there is something that only I can do in the job!
因為我能在這工作找到 只有我能做的事情
It was a lie, of course.
那是騙你的
I was acting cool.
我是在耍酷
I wanted to act cool!
我很想耍酷
I wanted to be cool
我希望，至少在你們面前 我是個很酷的人
Mr. Akagi…
赤城先生…
I wanted to be like you!
我是希望變得像你…
I wanted to become you, that's why I have kept working till today!
希望變成你才努力到現在的！
Don't be so frank, Mr. Akagi.
你別全都說出來，赤城先生
What?
什麼？
You acted cool in front of us once, didn't you?
你曾經在我們面前耍過酷吧？
An adult who acted cool once
曾經耍過酷的大人
shouldn't be so frank.
就不要把心裡想的都說出來
Mr. Akagi, a cool adult…
赤城先生，對小孩子來說
To us, when we were kids,
很酷的大人是燈台
you were the light that shone on darkness.
是照亮黑暗的明光
You were our guide!
是路標啊
Please keep on doing the job for the rest of your life!
請你就這樣一輩子負起這個責任吧
You were once our light, weren't you?
你曾經成為了我們的燈台，不是嗎？
Then keep the fighting spirit and act cool for the rest of your life!
那你就一生咬緊牙關繼續耍酷啊
What's wrong with you, Mr. Akagi?
你是怎麼了，赤城先生？
Don't be frank about something so stupid!
別連這麼無聊的事也對我們說
Don't put out the light that we used to believe in!
別熄滅了我們相信的明光！
Act cool! Keep acting cool for us!
繼續耍酷，一直耍酷下去啊！
Shut up!
閉嘴！
You didn't put any bullets in it, did you?
你根本就沒放子彈進去吧？
The Mr. Akagi I know
我認識的赤城先生
can't point a loaded gun at a kid.
不會把放了子彈的槍指向小孩 他就是這樣的大叔
He is not here anymore.
他已經不在了
That Mr. Akagi is not here!
這種赤城先生已經不在了！
Keebou!
希少！
I knew you were Mr. Akagi.
你果然是赤城先生
Ponjara.
碰將
Do your best in your job.
你要好好努力
I will.
我會的
Gosh, these guys are persistent!
這些傢伙還真煩
It's fine, guys.
夠了，你們
You can go home now. You're dismissed.
你們可以回去了，解散吧
Mr. Akagi!
赤城先生…
I'm sorry.
對不起
I made you work extra for the amount you got.
要你們做這種要花更多錢的事情
Mr. Akagi…
赤城先生
We didn't help you for the money.
我們幫你的忙
It's because we owe you so much,
是因為我們欠你的人情 一輩子也還不完
I knew it.
果然
They are all people
他們所有人
who Mr. Akagi had helped.
都是赤城先生曾經幫助過的人
HAYASHIDA LAUNDRY SHOP
（林田洗衣店）
Yuta.
優太
Don't tell dad and mom about today.
今天的事，爸和媽那邊…
I…
我…
I still hate to fight with others.
我還是討厭打架
I see.
是嗎？
So I will find my own way to fight.
所以我會找到自己的作戰方式
So that I can get the life I want.
為了得到自己想要的現在
Okay.
這樣啊
I am…
我是…
myself.
我自己
When I heard your voice, Keebou,
我聽到希少聲音的時候
I felt warm inside.
我覺得好溫暖
My heart…
我的心…
was racing.
跳得好快
Oh, did you?
是嗎？
When I heard you call my name, this place… felt warm, too.
我也是，聽到妳叫我
That's called romance.
那就是愛情吧？
What the heck are you saying? It's not, idiot.
你在說什麼？當然不是，笨蛋
Then what is it?
那是什麼？
-What is it… -What is it?
-是什麼？
What?
什麼？
It's the bond between us.
是羈絆吧？
Wow, you're acting cool, aren't you?
-你耍什麼帥？我要吻你了 -不要
What are you planning to do?
現在有什麼打算？
She can stay at my place.
來我家吧
I'm in the shop during the day, and people can see my shop.
我白天一直會在，店裡也會有人
My grandma loves children, too.
奶奶也喜歡小孩子
Is it okay?
可以嗎？
In for a penny, in for a meal. Right, Ponjara?
一不吃，二不休，對嗎，碰將？
-Yeah. -It's "pound".
-是啊 -是“一不做”
-Too late to turn back the horse! -It's "ship"!
-騎馬難下啊 -是“虎”啦
I've told you many times! You're so stupid!
這是第幾次了？你真笨
I don't care anyway!
是哪個都無所謂吧？
"Sales department".
“營業部”
PREVIEW OF NEXT EPISODE
（下集預告）
Keebou was taken away!
希少他被警察帶走了
Isn't the matter going to keep getting more serious?
總覺得這件事越來越誇張了
What can you do
妳現在能為希少做的
for Keebou right now?
就是要打起精神
No one will come to save me.
他們根本不可能會來救我
We're friends
不是能幫你的才叫朋友
because we want to help each other out.
是你想幫助的人，那才叫朋友